<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="94"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[https://www.facebook.com/share/p/15ii45Nm8t/]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I             Game-based Learning Day in Instrumental Analysis                                       I












          The  supervisor  team  of  the  Analytical  Chemistry  course  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  carried  out  an
          educational experiment with the goal of promoting a competitive and enjoyable atmosphere while motivating students
          to  comprehend  the  scientific  content.  In  addition,  it  is  motivating  students  to  improve  and
          expandtheir information acquisition abilities.


          On  Monday,  April  8th,  a  competition  was  held  between  several  student  teams  in  the  second-level  clinical
          pharmacy  laboratories.  The  competition  was  centered  around  a  game  that  promoted  visual  memory
          development  and  competitiveness,  with  the  educational  approach  being  learning  through  playing  game.






















































                                      https://www.facebook.com/share/p/EhzzqGeDYigCNEaq/






          12  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I         Devices for Drug Analysis with Local Egyptian Capabilities                                 I


                    Students At the Faculty of Pharmacy Invented Measuring








           Students of the Faculty of Pharmacy invented models for measuring devices for drug analysis with locally made
          Egyptian capabilities within the framework of the implementation of project-based education strategies, and under
          the patronage of Prof. Dr. CherifYoussefKhater- President of the University, and the leadership of Assos. Prof. Dr.
          Ahmed El-Sheikh  - Director of the Pharm D - Clinical  Pharmacy  Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy,  and the
          supervision of Prof.  Dr.  Jenny Jihan,  Dr.  Galal  Magdy,  and Dr.  Heba Samir  - course professors,  and teaching
          assistant in the Instrumental Analysis course.


           The students of the second level of the Pharm  D
           Clinical  Pharmacy  program  at  the  Faculty  of
           Pharmacy  designed  a  real  model  of automated
          analysis devices that work efficiently similar to the
          efficiency  of the  original  devices  with  simple
          capabilities, and this step reflects the importance of
          encouragmg  innovation  and  scientific  research
          in society.


           In  addition,  these  student  efforts  enhanced  the
          ability  to  provide  simple  and  effective
          technological  solutions,  contributing  to  the
          development  and improvement  of the  quality  of
          healthcare.




          For more details check the followings :





















           https://www.facebook.com/share/v/153PLKcoU6/?mibextid=oFDknk









                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  1 3]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I             Assessment for Learning (Application of the Education                                  I





                                Assessment System in Basic Pharmacology)








































          Within  the  framework  of  the  development  of         - Detailed  individual  feedback  is  provided  to  each
          teaching and learning systems, a new and innovative      student on the mid-term exam paper, in addition to
          assessment  system  was  implemented  for  the  first    organizing  individual  meetings  to  discuss  the
          time in the Basic Pharmacology course, which is the     weaknesses  and  strengths  of  each  student's
          assessment of learning.                                 performance  during  his  answers  in  the  exam.
                                                                  Feedback  is  made  on  information  related  to  the
          Assessment  for  learning,  to  enhance  the  quality  of   material  and  what  is  not  directly  related  to  the
          education  and  interaction  with  students.            material,  such as  handwriting,  writing method and
          -The  system  relies  on  providing  detailed  and      ability  to  express  in  English.We  believe  in  the
          customized  reference  feed  for  each  student  during  importance of personalized feedback and one-on-one
          each  stage  of  education,  through  several  channels:  meetings,  as  they  enhance student engagement and
          -During  each  week,  we  organize  assessment  tests   contribute  to  achieving  outstanding  learning
          whose  grades  are  not  added  to  the  total  subject  outcomes. This method allows the necessary support
          score,  through  which  students  can  measure  their   and guidance to improve performance, increases the
          understanding  of  the  weekly  lectures.  Students      student's  understanding  of  his  abilities  and
          receive instant feedback via the educational platform   encourages  him  to  continuous  development.
          in case of any errors. Solutions are also discussed in
          the lecture that follows.
          -After  the  end  of  the  exams,  including  mid-term
          exams  and  practical  exams,  we  provide  a            https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1XQpRfo73A/
          comprehensive  and  detailed  answer  form  either
          via  the  platform  or  during  the  following  lectures.



          14  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I        Organizing a Scientific Exhibition as Part of Analytical Chemistry                          I





                        Activities to Showcase Various Creative Student Projects




          Within the  framework  of project-based learning  and under  the  patronage  of Prof.  Dr.  Cherif Youssef Khater,
          President of the University,  and  the  leadership of Associate Assoc.  Prof.  Dr. Ahmed El-Sheikh, Director of the
           Pharma D - Clinical Pharmacy Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy,  and under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Jenny
           Gihan,  Dr.  Gala!  Magdy,  and Dr.  Reba Samir, course professors, with the participation and organization of the
          course's teaching assistants.

          The students of the Faculty of Pharmacy organized a scientific exhibition as part of the activities of the Analytical
          Chemistry  course  on  Sunday,  April  26th.  The  exhibition  showcased  numerous  creative  projects  that
          reflected the marvels of analytical chemistry, including presentations utilizing animation techniques and 3D models
          inspired  by  the  fundamentals  of  analytical  chemistry  and  advanced  analytical  instruments.

          During  the  exhibition,  students  applied  various  learning  strategies  such  as  self-learning,  simulation,
          brainstorming,  and  team  discussions  to  implement  an innovative  project  that contributes  to  expanding  their
          knowledge and shedding light on various analytical instruments.

















































                                        https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1AtgtiGdbk/


                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  1 5]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I       Biochemistry andCell Biology within the Framework of Project-Based                           I


                        Academic Student Activity Inspired by the Fundamentals of


                      Learning as Part of the "Donate Blood, Save a Life" Campaign




          Under  the  patronage  of Prof.  Dr.  Cherif Youssef  Khater,  President  of the  University,  and  the  leadership  of
          Associate Prof. Dr. Ahmed El-Sheikh, Director  of the Pharm D  - Clinical  Pharmacy  Program at  the  Faculty  of
          Pharmacy, and under the supervision of Assoc. Prof. Dr. Yousra El-Far and Associate Prof. Dr. Randa Zaghloul, the
          course professors, with the organization by the assisting staff, and as part of project-based learning activities within the
          "Donate  Blood,  Save  a  Life"  campaign,  pharmacy  students  presented  handmade  models  and  3D
          designs  inspired  by  the basics  of  biochemistry  and  cell biology  on  Tuesday, April  30th.  These  designs  were
          entirely created by the students.
























































                                         https://www.facebook.com/share/p/167YJZgTdM/






          16  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I                        Clinical Medical Scenario Simulation                                        I





                                   Using the Latest Simulation Systems





          To enhance the students' abilities at the university    Both the  Faculty  of Dentistry  and the  Faculty  of
          and  develop  their  scientific  skills,  under  the    Pharmacy conducted clinical case simulations from
          patronage  of  Prof.  Dr.  Cherif  Youssef  Khater,     April 27th to May  1st, using the latest simulation
          President  of  the  University,  and  the  leadership  of   systems.  The  aim  was  to  enhance  the  students'
          Prof.  Dr. Noha El-Wasifi, Director of the  Dentistry   experience  and  enable  them  to  acquire  the
          and  Oral  Surgery  Program  at  the  Faculty  of       necessary skills to practice the profession with high
          Dentistry,  and Assoc.  Prof.  Dr.  Ahmed  El-Sheikh,   efficiency.  The  simulation  included  a  variety  of
          Director  of  the  Pharm  D  - Clinical  Pharmacy       realistically  simulated  clinical  cases,  allowing
          Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy, and under the       students to practice medical procedures under the
          supervision  of  Dr.  Ahmed  Awad  and  Assis.  Lee.    supervision  of  faculty  members  from  both
          Abdel Rahman Amara.                                     faculties.  This  contributes  to  preparing  students
                                                                  and  equipping  them  to  face  modern  medical
                                                                  challenges.


                                                                  Training using clinical case simulation devices is
                                                                  an important step in developing medical education.
                                                                  Mansoura  National  University  is  committed  to
                                                                  providing a safe and realistic learning environment
                                                                  by  integrating  simulation  devices  into  the
                                                                  educational  process,  helping  students  gain  the
                                                                  skills necessary to interact with patients and deliver
                                                                  healthcare to the highest quality standards.



                                                                    https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1AhCEbD72a/






























                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  1 7]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I                    Using Glasses Meta Quest Virtual Reality 2                                      I



                                Organize a Microbiological Practical Test







           Towards the use of newer technologies in teaching and assessing students. Under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Cherif
          YoussefKhater, President of the University, and the leadership of Assoc. Prof. Dr. Ahmed El-Sheikh, Director of the
          Pharma D - Clinical Pharmacy Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy, and the supervision of Prof. Dr. Rasha Fathy,
           Professor  of Microbiology and Immunology, Ph. Ahmed Rizk and Ph. Yasmine Abed.  The Faculty of Pharmacy
          organized a test  using Meta Quest 2 virtual reality  glasses on Saturday  and Wednesday,  18  May  and 22 May,
           where the test is based on assessing the scientific and biological capabilities of the faculty in a practical manner by
          displaying a set of microbiological tests and the students interact with them and answer the questions received. The
          test aimed to measure students' biological and research capabilities, in addition to encouraging students to adapt to
          the latest technological means  in  the  modem  era,  which lead to the  expansion  of the  scientific  and  research
          knowledge of students.




















































                                        https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1C2JcToX7J/




                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  1 9]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I                               Microbiology and Immunology                                          I





                                                  Introductory Day







          Under  the  patronage  of  Prof.  Dr.  Cherif Youssef
          Khater- President of the University and the leadership
          of Assoc.  Prof.  Ahmed  El-Sheikh  - Director  of the
          Pharma D Clinical Pharmacy  Program at the  Faculty
          of Pharmacy,  under  the  supervision  of  Prof.  Rasha
          Fathi  Barwa,  Professor  of  Microbiology  and
          Immunology, and the supporting staff Dr Ahmed Rizk
          and  Dr.  Yasmine Abed  Department of Microbiology
          and  Immunology  - Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  an
          introductory  day  was  organized  on  18  and  22  May
          2024  for  microbiology  and  immunology  sciences,
          where second level students made  three-dimensional
          models that express the basic particles in this science
          and  learn  about  this  rich  world  of  microorganisms,
          including  the  cellular  structure  of  bacteria  and  the
          structure of the bacterial  cell wall, in addition to the
          most    important   principles   of    genetics,
          including  DNA,  RNA and  ribosomal  structure.  The
          day  also  included  the  identification  of  different
          antibodies  and  the  basics of mycology,  such as  the
          different  types  of  fungi, their reproduction methods,
          and  the  different  types  of  fungal  spores.

          The introductory day aims to raise students' awareness
           of  the  most  important  specialized  terms  in
           microbiology  that students  need  to  know throughout
           the years of study  and to expand  students' awareness
           of  the  latest  scientific  research  in  this  field.





















          https://www.facebook.com/share/v/1Ad3qJSY7n/?mibextid=wwXIfr



          20  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I          Course: Exhibition of Pharmaceutical Products Monday"                                     I


                     "Student Activity for the Pharmaceutical Preparations II








          Under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Cherif Youssef Khater, President of Mansoura National University, and Assoc.
          Prof.  Dr.  Ahmed  Ramadan  El-Sheikh, Director  of the  Pharm-D  Clinical  Pharmacy  Program,  and  under  the
          supervision of Dr. Ghada El-Imam, Dr. Walaa Ibrahim, and Dr. Randa Hani, course professors, with the organization
          of the assistant staff Assis. Lee. Aya Abu El-Fad!, Ph. Iman Mostafa, and Ph. Nerwied Tarek, and in line with the
          university's commitment to enhancing education based on student activities and practical projects, the instructors of
          the course "Pharmaceutical Preparations II" organized a student activity aimed at equipping students with skills in
          the manufacturing of various pharmaceutical preparations, while also developing and enhancing their marketing and
          promotional skills.

          Students watched videos uploaded by the course instructors, which included information about the disease to be
          treated and the active ingredients available for treatment using artificial intelligence technology. The students then
          prepared  the  appropriate  pharmaceutical  preparation  and  also  created  medical  promotions  for  it.  They  used
          innovative promotional methods such as posters, awareness videos, social media posts, and the creation of websites
          to highlight suitable pharmaceutical preparations for treating various diseases. This process allows students to apply
          theoretical knowledge in a practical and real-world context, thereby enhancing their practical and applied skills ..


                                                                           https://www.youtube.com/watch?












































           https://www.facebook.com/share/p/FiswwZW5qbRRnUE5/?m
                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  21]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v
          https://www.facebook.com/share/v/1Ad3qJSY7n/?mibextid=wwXIf]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I      Examinations for the Second Semester of the 2023-2024 Academic Year                           I



                       Mansoura National University President Examines the Final







          On  Saturday,  June  8,  2024,  in  the  university's  faculties,  Prof.  Dr.  Cherif  Youssef  Khater,
          President of Mansoura National University, conducted an inspection of the final exams for the second semester of
          the academic  year  2023-2024.  Mansoura  National  University  administration's  dedication  to  supervising  the
          examination process was demonstrated by this visit.

          Prof.  Dr.  Ra'efa  Allam,  the  dean  of  the  Faculty  of  Nursing,  Prof.  Dr.  Noha  AI-Waseefi,  the
          Director of the Faculty of Dentistry's Oral and Dental Surgery Program, and Assoc. Prof. Dr. Ahmed El-Sheikh, the
          Director of the Phanna D -Clinical Pharmacy Program at the Faculty of Phannacy, accompanied him on the visit.


























                                                                   https://www.facebook.com/share/p/KJkcbNbn7JbSiiwt/

































                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  23]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I              Activity Fostered Personal and Professional Growth                                    I



                            Exploring the Self: A Co-curricular Psychology







          As part of an innovative enhancement to the psychology curriculum, the "Exploring the Self' co-curricular activity
          was  implemented  to  provide  students  with  a  more  practical  and  behaviorally  grounded  learning  experience.
          The  activity aimed to connect psychological theory  with  the  everyday behaviors students encountered in  their
          communities,  thereby  promoting  self-awareness,  emotional  intelligence,  and  socially  constructive  behavior.  The
          initiative  focused on assessing  students'  personalities  through a range  of standardized  psychological assessments.
          These tools were used to evaluate both individual and group behavioral tendencies. Based on the results, each student
          received personalized feedback and developmental advice from trained faculty mentors. These one-on-one sessions
          aimed to support the students in understanding their psychological profiles and guide them toward more positive and
          effective behaviors-both personally and socially.


          This activity was delivered through the REACH Platform, a digital tool developed by the Faculty of Pharmacy at
          Mansoura National University. The platform was designed as a comprehensive psychological and career development
          interface.  It supported students in identifying  potential career paths and entrepreneurial aspirations based on their
          personality  traits,  values,  and  preferences.  Through  this  platform,  students  were  able  to  explore  their  unique
          psychological makeup and receive tailored career suggestions. The results of the assessments provided a structured
          overview  of  their  behavioral  patterns  and  value  systems.  Faculty  mentors  interpreted  these  results  during
          individualized  sessions, helping students  understand their strengths  and  developmental  areas  while guiding  them
          toward careers that aligned with their profiles. Importantly, the platform allowed for adaptability: students who wished
          to  reflect  further  or  reconsider  their  assessment  outcomes  were  supported  through  ongoing  mentorship  and
          re-assessment, fostering a mindset of continuous personal growth.

          This co-curricular experience not only enhanced students' psychological insight but also empowered them to make
          informed decisions about their professional futures.  It exemplified an educational shift toward integrating academic
          knowledge with real-world applications in personal and career development.


                                                                 our Mission

                                      "The  leadership  in  providing  training  and  employment  for  pharmacists
                    REACH             across Egypt."

                    mmml
                    Personal Asscssmcnr                                           Abou t us
                    Training Tracks
                                                                                  REACH platform is an electronic
                                                                                  tool for reach society.
                                                                                  facilitating skill enhancement
                                                                                  and career direction based on a
                                       �EACH                                      analysis. Moreover, we will
                                                                                  personalized psychometric
                                                                                  assess students'
                                                                                  entrepreneurial aspirations.


                                      ContactUS       Emal!:�                    in  O  :%
                                                      Follow Us on social media
                                      https://sites.google.com/mans.edu.eg/reachmnu/home
         24  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I                         T h rough Virtual Reality Simulations                                      I



                                    Enhanced Tuberculosis Education







          In a  pioneering  step  towards  integrating  technology  into  pharmacy  education,  students  from  the  Faculty  of
          Pharmacy at Mansoura National University conducted a virtual reality (VR) simulation focused on Mycobacterium
          tuberculosis  (the  bacterium responsible for tuberculosis)  on  Saturday,  April  6.  Supervised by  faculty  members,
          Microbiology  department,  this  initiative  aimed  to  replicate  the  real-life  behavior  of tuberculosis  bacteria  in  a
          controlled, immersive environment. The simulation allows for in-depth exploration of microbiological interactions
           without  the  health  risks  associated  with  traditional  lab  work.  This  approach  enhances  students'  practical
          understanding,  fosters  innovation,  and  provides  a  cost-effective  and  safe  alternative  for  scientific
          experimentation and disease research.

























































                                       https://www.facebook.com/share/p/14GDH74MPjK/



                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  25]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I                   A Silent Threat to Maternal and Fetal Health                                     I



                              Raised Awareness About Rh Incompatibility:






          The  Faculty  of Pharmacy  at  Mansoura  National  University  continued  its  commitment  to  community  health
          awareness by shedding light on Rh incompatibility-a medical condition that poses serious risks to expectant mothers
          and their unborn children.  This  condition occurs when the  blood  types  of the mother and fetus are incompatible,
          potentially resulting in severe complications if not properly managed. An educational video produced by our students
          explored the dangers of Rh incompatibility, the importance of early detection, and the necessary preventive measures
          to  ensure a healthy  pregnancy. Through this initiative, we aimed to  empower women with essential knowledge to
          safeguard their own health and that of their babies.



              Symptoms
           ,\/                       Causes
             Rh incompatibility can cause
                      i             During pregnancy, if the
             s�\l'J'���!!��� l����ild:;r   mother is Rh-negative, her
                      8       s    immune  system treats the
            fo;;,n;:• :e�{���ti'J'n �r��lj' �/';,';!;  Rh-positive  fetal cells as if
              calls. There are no other�     f
                   effects.        sui���n�=�T�e �:���r's
                                    body forms antibodies
              After birth  infant may
                    h ��� ,        against the  fetus's blood
            •  •  Yellowing of the  skin and   cells.
             whites of the eyes Qaundice)
                  and lethargy  d
             Low muscle tone  (hypotonia)   b When red blood cells are  e   RH
                                   b�f;:�b1:��i:�:�r:i��
                                     infant to  turn yellow   INCOMPATIBILITY
                                    ijaundice). The  level of
             Treatmen't           bilirubin in an infant's blood
                                    may range  from mild to
                                      dangerously high.
              Infants with mild Rh   Rh incompatibility  develops
           ncompatibility may be treated   only when the  mother is  Rh
            with phototherapy using   negative and the infant is
            bilirubin lights. IV immune
           lobulin may also be used. For   Rh positive.
           infants severely affected< an   11111
            change transfusion of b1ood
            may be  needed. This is to                                         https://www.facebook.com/share/p/19yBn4sjvc/
           ecrease  the levels of bilirubin   SCAN ME
                in the blood.

















                                                                          Milli
          https://youtu.be/tD_pERAPqjk?si=XqkNDvG7sQyCdx7j
                                                                           SCAN ME






         26  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I                    Explored Neonatal Jaundice: Knowledge Is                                        I





                               the First Step Toward Healthy Beginnings







          Neonatal  jaundice  remains  one  of  the  most
          common  yet  misunderstood  conditions  affecting
          newborns. Characterized by a yellow discoloration
          of the skin and eyes, jaundice evokes concern and                            E
          uncertainty  among  new  parents.  In  a  student-led         .,_ -
          awareness  campaign,  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy        FINITION:
          sought  to  demystify this condition by  addressing
          its  causes,  implications,  and  available  treatments.   AUNDICE, ALSO KNOH AS HVPERBLIRUBINEMIA, IS A
                                                              EU.OW DISCOLORATION OF THE SKIN, TISSUES, AND
          The  campaign  emphasized  that  with  timely       ODY FLUIDS. IT IS CAUSED av THE DEPOSrrlON OF
          intervention  and  parental  awareness,  neonatal   LE PIGIENTS. MANY MEDICAL CONDrrlONS CAN
          jaundice  can  be  effectively  managed.  The  full   AUSE JAUNDICE, LICE HEPATrrlS, GALI.STONES AND
                                                              UMORS.
          educational video was made available as part of our
          effort to promote health literacy and early diagnosis
          for  the  well-being  of  our  youngest  patients.
                                                                  SYMPTOMS:             COMPLICATIONS:
           To  learn  more,  check  out  the  full  tutorial:
                                                              HE PRNARY SYMPTOM IS    PROLONGED HVPERBIURUBINEMIA
                                                              ELLOWISH__DISCOLORATION OF   CAN RESULT IN CHRONIC 8ILIRU81N
                                                              HE WHITE PART OF             ENCEPHALOPATH QUICK
                                                              HE EYES AND SKIN               AND ACCURATE
                                                                                             TREATMENT OF
                                                                                              NEONATAL JAUNDICE
                                                                                              HELPS TO REDUCE
                                                                                              THE RISK OF NEONATES
                                                                                               DEVELOPING.




              https://www.facebook.com/share/p/16XhiJ4wNW/
                                                                 BABES •rrH NEONATAL JAUNDICE MAV BE TREATED
                                                                 •rrH COLORED LIGHT CALLED PHOTOTHERAPV, •HICH
                                                                 •oRKS BV CHANGING TRANS-BLIRUBIN INTO THE
                                                                 •ATER-SOLUBLE CIS-BLIRUBIN ISOMER THE
                                                                 PHOTOTHERAPV INVOLVED IS NOT ULTRAVIOLET LIGHT.
                                                                             DIAGNOSIS:
                                                                           DIAGNOSIS IS OFTEN BV MEASURING THE SERUM
                                                                           BD.IRUBIN LEVEL IN THE BLOOD IN THOSE WHO ARE
                                                                           BORN AFTER 35 WEEKS AND ARE MORE THAN A DAY
                                                                    ....-:».n  OLD.


            https://youtu.be/Iu6Zd9Ew_I8?si=d5l13qOfb47E_L-d










                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2  127]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I                Launched Campaign Against Hepatitis B and C:                                        I





                               Promoted Awareness and Early Detection




          In line with global health initiatives, the Faculty of Pharmacy launched a campaign to raise awareness about Hepatitis
          B and C-two viral infections that often go undetected until significant damage has occurred. These "silent" diseases
          often remain asymptomatic for years, yet they  carry the risk of liver  failure,  cancer,  and even death if untreated.
          Through  a series of  informative sessions  and  digital content,  this  campaign educated  the  public on  transmission
          methods, symptoms, and the importance of early screening and medical care. We remained committed to equipping
          individuals  with  the  tools  and  information  necessary  to  protect  their  health  and  that  of  their  communities.

            https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?
            story_fbid=pfbid02VaweGhVk2KKMP8funq3AcwUsC1HQSDoUJENJ7oKFJJKjNUbFzHTAumWgAvvJQu1Hl&id=100085446049506

               ow do 1 know that I
             have hep  iti  C v rus?




                                        1 e  atiti  C
               Fever and fatigue                              Hepat1t·
                                     One of the most  common
                Loss of app  tlt  and   diseases  that affect the liver and
                 abdominal pain      c n  caus  acute and chron c
                                     dis  ans (such as c rrhos s and   C and  B
               N  us   and vomiting
                                ..   c  nc  rous llv  r  tumors)
                   Dark  urine

             Ytilowlng of the skin and eyes
                    (J  undlce)     bc!Yng1ng n

                  Treatment


            https://youtu.be/gtbdcg0h86E?si=1lNnFq8R65Oxwa2N
                                                                  become infect  d
                                                                      Hepa! Is B


                                        Hepatitis B can be       Virus B h   the s  m  causes
                                          prevented by           s Virus C, but th  differ  nc  s   H
                                                                           r  :
                                         vaccines that are
                                                                                       Hepatl  s B Is a v ral  nfec  on that
                                          safe , available       Contact with blood or   pr m  r11y aff  cu th  llv  r  a nd can
                                           and effective         other body fluids ,such   lead to both acute  and  chronic
                                                                 ass  llva  m ...  diseases.
                                                                                              SYWJOMSO,-,msl



                                                                 :rr  nsmttted from mother
                                                                 to chold du, ng b;J


                                                                                                          ..
                                                                                                       ---


         28  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I     Dispelled Myths About Anemia: More Than Just Iron Deficiency                                   I












          As part of our educational outreach, our faculty addressed a common misconception about anemia-namely, that it
          is  caused  solely  by  iron  deficiency.  In  reality,  anemia  can  arise  from  various  factors,  including vitamin  B 12
          deficiency,  chronic diseases,  and genetic  conditions. An awareness flyer developed by our students  focused  on
          permc1ous anemia.  The  flyer provides insights  into its symptoms,  causes, and prevention strategies,  aiming to
          enhance  public  understanding  and  promote  early  diagnosis  through  increased  awareness.




                                                                      Whatf;J, the,pe!U anem ?
                                                                                                ...
                                                                                Sympl  • ••
           _,;1.wl (.;,,.,i4,s') 12 y .:,,t:,; -,.,1.,.1 .,.i l,.;Li,;1-,.. l,., ,,v _,.;1; _,..L:.. yl_,;.1 ,-.  �I r.i.11   rnicious anemia is a relatively rare autoimmune disorder that causes diminishment in
           -        . ._;.)Ul.:.l.,,'J1,..;.:.J1r.i.ll_,ii,12y.:,,t:,;.;,_)!..s•.Y.l...   1ctary vitamin Bu (cobalamin) absorption, resulting in Bu deficiency and subsequent
                                 �l��I                        cgaloblastic anemia.
                                                              omc people do not have symptoms. Symptoms may be mild.
            f ...   0�   1·                                     Slmrlnessof   Lossofappetite   fatigue   �   constipalion
                                                                            exertion
                                                                                                       Diarrhea or
                                                                 brcalh
                                                                                                   �
                   �    --                                                                 ID e         f ...
            ,iJlt-,11                                                Pale skin    light.headedness   ,   Nausea
                    �                                                                      ,
             dl-,,il
                        ��I �.l.Jl���J.JILA                          What cmMep.etanem?
           . lfj o.>l,.o l.4i �L:..I "1:,IP. � L.=.!,.... ._,;1.iJI �L:..I ..,.1ri .:,. ;;Jb, ,a, �I r..ul   ernicious anemia is an autoiinn1une condition that happens \Vhen your imn1un
           � � o,,.; � -  l:..I  d:,IP. 4-!�I }_;; . ..,.i li,�1, o.... ;.,,i,;.I  ;.;u..,1..} 1/.   stem produces antibodies that attack cells in the mucosa( lining of yourstomac
                     ,r
                             .12y.:,,l::, _,ol,.,I            nd nerve cells. Your immune system's response affects your body's ability to
                                                                                'Pruw.
                                                               sorb vitamin B12.
            .:.l>'ll ... 11,;;.,I .:.l'Wldl,-)J'll> .:,.  )oi...IJ.,I � .:,S, .  .!.,I r..ul ..,i .!.,.1.>�  • •   ou can't prevent pernicious anemia from occurring. But you can reduce your risk by
            JL1 . .!.,I r.i.11 _,.; .:,� 1..ik...:. 1;1.12 y.:,,t:,; -,.,1.,.1 ��-,  ... �  ;;; ,.; ._.:1-  eing aware of medical conditions, treatments and activities that may affect your
           12 y .:,,t:,; _,.. � �;i,;.1 � ,.:JI .:.1,.._I ,t> l., p..} c.:. 1;! � "1,! -,., WI .,;.1 "I.   ody's ability to absorb vitan1in BIZ. If you're concerned about pernicious anemia, ask
                           �    ••   ·- j�                    our healthcare provider if you're at risk and what steps you can take to avoid vitamin
                                                              12  deficiency.
                            ��                                            �do,[/ takeca,woC,l1UJ?
           •i/.jJl.)o.:rB12 _,..._s,_;.'ilyl,-,'ili""L-. � .dil,>.,.,ru;;.4,2y.:,,t:,;.:.:,W; J,i:; .)!ct  -  ou'll need to take vitamin 812s upplements regularly for the rest of your life. Other causes o
             a,,.4l.ilM!l"1.oU,;,.)!�1.,.!,,_;.,,sl"'-",,.:l....'J1..,;_,...,,;1;..i1"1.ou;.;,,_;512.;,,�   1.2  deficiency may be helped by increasing the vitamin BIZ in your diet. Some foods to
                                                              nsider adding to your diet include:
                                                    B

                                              J!,..1..z���WJ.JI-  Foods fortified with vil:unin Bil,   Eggs and dairy
                              J!.).:.1,h1.:.�,_,.;1             such as soy-based beverages and   products (such as milk.   Breakfast cereals with added
                               . (,;,,-�,JI' .;,,!JI' -,..I   ,<  .,,n, 4,  ..  n J_,i .,i. :wt.i!1 .:.t,,   vegetarian burgers   yogurt and cheese).   vil;:unin 81.z
                                                    _,; l,;JI


          For more information check out the full tutorial:



                              https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?             https://youtu.be/
                              story_fbid=pfbid02N2ntTbVwQVazEWKXYgLjU8            fKIAFxsZKN8?
                              7YTpXpurqkvCCMgVmmhpFQqAEuN9EaMc2d5                 si=vLuYAOsuwar2ZPsd
                              VDXphiWl&id=100085446049506









                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2  129]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[https://www.facebook.com/share/p/VRS7crysEd2TYU]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I                           Awareness Campaign on Malaria                                            I





                                              Friday, May 10, 2024




            1
           lt s  not  just  a  bite;  it's  a  potential  threat!  Be  6.Community    Engagement          and
           proactive in the fight against malaria. This students'   Outreach:  Encouraging  pharmacy  students  and
          campaign  focused on educating the university and       faculty to actively participate in outreach activities,
           surrounding  community  about  malaria,  its           including  health  talks,  free  screenings,  and  the
          prevention, and the role of phannacy professionals      distribution  of  preventive  tools  like  bed  nets.
          in  managing  the  disease.  Key  aspects  of  the
          campaign included:                                      7.Collaboration  with  Health  Authorities:
                                                                  Strengthening  partnerships  with  local  health
           I.Introduction    to   Malaria:     Raising            organizations  to  enhance  malaria  awareness,
          awareness about the causes, symptoms, and global        prevention,    and     treatment     efforts.
           impact  of  malaria,  with  a  special  focus  on  its
          prevalence     and    control   in    Egypt.            This campaign did not only raise awareness about
                                                                  malaria  but also highlighted the crucial role that
                                                                  pharmacy professionals play in fighting the disease
          2.Prevention  Strategies:  Educating  the public
          on effective malaria prevention methods,  such as       and promoting public health.
          using  insecticide-treated  bed  nets,  eliminating
          mosquito  breeding  sites,  and  other  vector
          control measures.


           3.Pharmacists'      Role    in    Malaria                                         -,
          Management:  Highlighting  how  pharmacy                                          , ......... -....
          professionals  can  contribute  to  malaria  control,            'M:■Larh,l10Uto - th .. 11tc,nlngdl1■■ ..   '"E'  -•=-- =�
                                                                           •  1ron1mlttlld to human■ by soma
                                                                            1pt•donot mosqult-s.M1l.arl1 b
                                                                           1p,e1d mainly In tropluolcounuln
                                                                                           �=·- ·=--
          including  patient  education,  proper  use  of                   ■nd un b■ p,eventlld ■nd cur.d   ·=   =
                                                                                           -- - - ,-·----
                                                                                              -l,-
          anti-malarial  medications,  and  counseling  on                             qi  fit�   <Sfl  cf/   ii,
          drug adherence.                                                              E,rtre,...  .. hau1tlon1"6t1tlgu1
                                                                                       lmpalNldconaclou....u
                                                                                       MultlpWinlsurH
                                                                                       BNAthlngdlttln.L\ty
                                                                                       Darkorbtoodurl,..
                                                                                       hundl c11)'9ll.owlngofthll)'H ... 1llln.}
                                                                                       Abnormalbleedl r,g
          4.Current  Malaria  Situation  in  Egypt:
          Discussing  the  malaria  situation  in  Egypt,  the
          ongoing  efforts  to  combat  the  disease,  and  the              (1)PlamodlumY1,..,..[P.,J­
                                                                             mortwld1l,dlrtrlbut.d
                                                                             WPl.amodlumo.rat.(P.-.1•
                                                                             ttoenrerttype
          importance  of  community  involvement.                            (3)!PLlamodlumrna!.arl11
                                                                             (Pm)-not .. wldHpreH
                                                                             (lo) Plnmodlum f■lclpuum
                                                                             (PfJ-ttu.mo1tdang110U1
                                                                            ·==--..
          5.Distribution  of  Educational  Materials:                       ?ntvenlw:>oo!   �
                                                                            Malaria  .ti  -
                                                                            =--...:.:.
          Providing leaflets,  posters,  and online resources               :�:-�      u ..... ei•""'ll••• .... ,-,,.po{i.nt.
                                                                            -·--.
                                                                                       -a,lo"9"1i.-.d1hl"1andio.,.-u.
                                                                                       TN-etcl.oltll1>9•n4 .... whhpe-rtnfhnn.
          with  key  information on malaria prevention and                  "'::..:.;--  llNpmosq>dtonOV1ofyo11rhou,I....
                                                                                       lla•p11IMln•mosqulUlo..t.
                                                                            -�-;:.::
          treatment options.
                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  31]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Chapter 1
          I                             HIV Awareness Information                                              I












           In  the  intricate  of global  health  challenges,  HIV emerges  as  a  formidable  foe  as  the  causative  agent  of AIDS.
          HIV persists as a huge public health concern globally. Despite notable strides in treatment and prevention, an alarming
           1.3  million individuals acquired HIV in 2022.  Hence, students made this awareness spreading initiative, aiming to
          dispel  misconceptions surrounding HIV/ AIDS,  by  delving  into  the  disease's intricacies, transmission  dynamics,
          and societal repercussions to empower individuals towards informed choices.
































                                                             SYMPTOMS























                                        https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xHj_P3ZOXUg

                                              https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid






         32  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Co-curricular Student Activities

         I                            Awareness About Thalassemia                                             I












             Thalassemia can cause mild
              or severe anemia and other
               complications over time
               (such as iron overload).
             Symptoms of anemia include
              •          Fatigue .
              •     Trouble breathing  .
              •        Feeling cold  .
              •         Dizziness  , .                                               �-=-'-'.a
                                                                                        Definition:  n· ffl
              •
             ''         Pale skin.               Alpha           Beta        Thllnllmia Is M lnhl blood dlsardar

                                             This condition occurs when
                                              one or more of the lour   This blood disorder affects   when the body dDlll make
                                                              the production ol
                                              genes responsible for
                 Can I prevent thalassemia?   making hemoglobin are   hemoglobin   I prat. called llemaplbln, M llfflPrtln
               Because thalassemia is passed from   lackl119 or damiCJM.   and Is caused by two   part of red blood cellL When there Isn't
                                                               specillc 9,n,.s
               parents to children, It Is very hard to   TRALEMIA             enough a.maglabln, the body's red blood
                        prevent                                              cell don't hmctn property and they Int
                                                                             sharr peri of tlmt, ID thn 11'8 fnlr
                                                                              healthy red blood eels trnellng In the
                                                                                        bloa
                                                                                                   .. ...
                Ulood transfusions.                                               Normal          Thalsumla
               Llron chelation therapy.
              3-8one marrow transplant.
             ltJallc add supplementation.
                 s_suppartiw• car■.



           Thalassemia,  a  complex  genetic  disorder,  casts  a  shadow  of  uncertainty  over  the  lives  of  millions
          worldwide.  This  enigmatic  condition,  characterized  by  abnormal  hemoglobin  production,  presents  a
          multifaceted challenge to healthcare professionals and patients as well. As we delve into the intricacies of this
          hematological  enigma,  it  becomes  clear  that  awareness  is  the  key  to  unlocking  the  door  for  better
          management and improved quality of life for those afflicted.  Join us as we embark on a journey to unravel the
           mysteries of thalassemia and check out the full tutorial.

           For more details check the followings :





                                                 https://www.youtube.com/watch?
                                                 https://www.facebook.com/share/p/eJ36JxPztEdQAiXY/?mibextid=oFDknk




                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  33]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                                Mansoura National University Participates in
                                  Its First Event with Horus University Rally





           In its first participation in the Horus University Rally, Mansoura National University supported the promotion of an
          entrepreneurial  culture  and  the  creation  of  student  projects  that  enable  them  to  generate  diverse  job
          opportunities. Under the patronage of Prof. Cherif Khater, the University President, and Assoc. Prof. Dr. Ahmed
           El-Sheikh,  Director  of the Pharm-D  Clinical  Pharmacy  Program,  and  in  the  presence  of Dr.  Randa  Hany,
           Coordinator  of  the  University  Rally  Team,  and Mr.  Hassan Abou  El-Wafa,  Head  of Student Activities  at  the
           University, a delegation of 25 students, led by student Huda Hegazi, participated on Monday, February 13th, 2024, in
          the Delta Universities Rally held at Horus University.

           The  Rally  team  aims  to  foster  an  entrepreneurial  spirit  among  students  by  encouraging  them  to
          develop their own projects, creating new and diverse job opportunities. This event is part of the Entrepreneurship
           Rally competition organized in cooperation with the Arab Academy for Science, Technology, and Maritime Transport,
          during  which  student  projects  are  submitted  for  evaluation.  It  also  provides  students  with  an
          opportunity  to  develop  their  entrepreneurial  and  innovative  skills,  enhance  their  community  involvement,  and
          interact with other universities.








































           For more details check the followings :

                                https://www.facebook.com/share/p/9q1PSYiTZXAnMu27/?mibextid=WC7FNe
                                                      [!] .   I   [!]
                                                      :-'I :JOT_::_-___,,.,. c,,-_ _:o.




          36  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[-------------------------- Extra-curricular Student Activities





                 Students Activities Management Is Organizing a Recreational and Cultural

                 Trip to Cairo for University Students in Collaboration with the PMD Team




            Under the patronage of Prof. Dr. CherifYoussef Khater, the University President, and under the leadership of Mr.
            Mohamed      Abdel     Latif,   General    Supervisor     of   the    Education     and    Student
            Affairs  Sector,  and  Assoc.  Prof.  Dr.  Ahmed  El-Sheikh,  Director  of  the  Pharm  D  - Clinical
            Pharmacy  Program  and the  Academic  Supervisor  of Student  Activities  at  the  University,  and  under  the
            superv1s1on  of  Mr.  Hassan  Abu  El          Wafa,   Student  Activities  Supervisor  at  the
            University,  and  Dr.  Karim  El  Maddawy,  Student  Affairs  Officer  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy.


            The  Student  Activities  Department  organized  an  entertaining  and  cultural  trip  for  university
            students  in  cooperation  with  the  PMD  team  on  Thursday,  May  2nd.  They  traveled  to  Cairo  to
            explore  its  landmarks  and  learn  about  its  rich  history.  During  the  trip,  the  students  enjoyed
            visiting prominent historical sites in Cairo, including the Citadel of Salah al-Din al-Ayyubi and Heliopolis, where
            they   were     captivated   by    the   beauty    of    the   ancient   architecture    and   the
            magnificence of ancient Egyptian civilization.


            This trip comes as part of the efforts of Mansoura National  University  to enhance the cultural and historical
            awareness  of  its  students,  aiming  to  familiarize  them  with  the  importance  of  these  landmarks  and  their
            contribution to shaping Egypt's national and cultural identity.







































             https://www.facebook.com/share/p/Hayy5DLeRrYmF

             https://www.facebook.com/share/1FrEBC6d7p/



                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2  I 37]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                             "Who Paved the Way"Celebration of International
                               Women's Day at Mansoura National University





           On  Wednesday,  March  8th,  2024,  as  part  of  Mansoura
           National  University's  celebration  of  International
           Women's  Day,  the  Pharmacy  Student  Scientific
           Association (PSA) at the university  organized an event titled
           "Who Paved the Way" in collaboration with the University's
           Quality,  Accreditation,  and  Community  Engagement
           Committee,  under  the patronage  of Prof.  Cherif  Khater,  the
           University  President,  and the  leadership  of Assoc.  Prof.  Dr.
           Ahmed  El-Sheikh,  Director  of  the  Pharm  D  - Clinical
           Pharmacy Program



           and  Coordinator  of  Quality,  Accreditation,  and  Community  Engagement  Committee  at  the
           University.  The  event  was  supervised  by  Dr.  Basant  Maher  - PSA  coordinator,  and  included
           participation from Dr. Randa Hany and Dr. Yomna EI-Leithi.


           Objectives of the Event
           The event aimed to celebrate and acknowledge the invaluable contributions of women in society, science, and
           academia. It highlighted the significance of empowering women, promoting gender equality, and recognizing their
           roles  in  shaping  the  future.  PSA  focused  on  fostering  an  environment  that  encourages  collaboration  and
           empowerment,  emphasizing  how  women  have  been  pivotal  in  advancing  education,  research,  and  the
           healthcare sector.


          Engaging Discussions and Activities:

          The event featured a series of engaging discussions and activities centered around critical issues related to women's
          health and well-being. The included sessions delved into the importance of mental health care for women and its
          impact  on  the  quality  of  life  for  both  women  and  their  families.  Topics  covered  included:


          •Nutrition:  Understanding dietary needs and the importance of nutrition for women across different life stages.
          •Cosmetics:  Exploring  the  beauty  industry's  impact  on  women's  self-esteem  and  health.
          •Common  Diseases:  Discussing  prevalent  health  issues  among  women  and  preventive  measures.
          •Women's  Health  Across  Life  Stages:  Addressing  the  unique  health  challenges  women  face  from
          adolescence to menopause and beyond.

           For more details check the followings :





                                  https://fb.watch/qMBG-Ib1j3/
                                  https://www.facebook.com/100084712745066/posts/376515275182228/?
                                  mibextid=rS40aB7S9Ucbxw6v




         38  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                                          Promoting Health Awareness:
                                 "A Fact a Day" Campaign During Ramadan






          Pharmacy Students  Scientific Association (PSA) launched a campaign titled "A Fact a Day" during  the holy month
                                                                     p
          of Ramadan under the patronage of  Prof. Cherif Khater,  University  r esident,  the leadership of Assoc.  Prof. Ahmed
                                                                                  o
          R.    El-Sheakh,    Pharm-D    (clinical   Pharmacy)    p r ogram   d i rect r ,   and   superv1s1on   of
          Dr.    Bassant   Maher,    P S A   coordinator.   The   m1tiat1ve   aims   to   provide   individuals,
          especially those with various health conditions, with valuable information and  health practices to follow during this
          blessed  month     through  daily  p o s t s   including   29  postswith  different  health  knowledge.







                              - /�       /
                              7              /
                                                /
                              rv u        r--"V'
                                -!0 ✓  j  ·r'IA
                              17
             • ,$_µ\ �) �\41.i yil-I � J .)�  A.o\$.  �I:_. j  •      in the
                      • -½�  ,-1;� ,-1,Lo� J-,
               J':>\ '>½.W y_,,ll � j': ..,. .u <)l.A., R  J,i y_,,ll � }- l.aiJ
                                    )
                             .!l)\,11 .:,l.A.) R
                µ1J1.,,.J�),-1..,w-fa  ,;tk.i)'l4-;�.i.;.y  ;1)\..A)J,.i  \.,-y.O
                                                    f'                 Month of
                                -r.ul  j__, '-,- _y,I
                                J
              }�..JI .;\5' 1;!_,  •;_,,.l � J   }k.i)II 4- � �  ),-1  .i.;._;;  ;<)\.Ao J,.i  \:-'  .f.  �  f'
                                             )
                                                                            amadan
                  .__.. ;_,,.l � ,,,.  J).i; H i;sl y i..5
                     Gllbonclomlde
                    I  --------










                                                                        •         -------"


                 ii.ag.w,p9,1 J.5                                             V'-A�./1-7-$
                                 =u� � -,J.aJ1 '-:19.,,                                �\ l/ �\ �v--°
                                     J
                ��""11i)..��i;;l '-/:l.i.al .:i�I J91i.i�
                 4�J.i:tli)..o�l!:19.>J91i.i�,-. ��J.i!�l9
                              . .:i�Lwi
                         ��
                                ,.i.>,.>-IOO•....,..;.








          40  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Chapter 2






                                      "World Autism Awareness Day"






           Every year on 2nd April, people commemorate World
           A u tism  Awareness  Day.  The  United  Nations  General
           Assembly  declared  it in  2007  with  the  intention  of
           improving acceptance of people with autism, supporting
           the role of those with autism in society, and expanding
           knowledge of the spectrum of autism and its symptoms.
           On the occasion of World Autism A w areness Day, PSA
           students organized  a digital  awareness  campain about
           autism  on  social  media  including  its  myths  and  facts
           with  other  awareness  information,  under  the
           patronage  of  the  university  president  and  the
           leadership of the  Pharm-D  program director  with  the
                v
           super i sion  of  PSA  coordinator,  aimed  to
           rnc r ease   awareness   about    this   disease                        WORLD
           in Egyptian society.                                              AUTISM
                                                                             AVVARE.   E.$5  DA,





                                                                                          . ..
                                                                                          :.i,;i.;
                                                                                          '.P'SAl
                                      Only boys                                   People with
                                                                                      autism
                                              are                                      do  't

                                         autistic

                     AUTISM
                    AWARENESS       Autism Myths               AWARENESS       Autism Myths
                            DAY                                       DAY
                           1"0A.PR\L





                                            Autistic

                                        people ha¥                             Autistic people

                                           a  pecial                               cannot learn


                                             talent            AUTISM

                    AWARENESS       Autism Myths               AWARENESS       Autism Myths
                            DAY                                        DAY
                                                                      2NDAPftlL  _________ _
                              https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=1130829654933698&rdid=dip20HrunsBou5aQ
         42  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities






                                        "World Down Syndrome Day"






             For this significant day, the Faculty of Pharmacy   Key Areas to Focus On:
             at  Mansoura National  University joins  the global
                                                                Medical Awareness:  Understanding the healthcare
             celebration of World Down  Syndrome Day. This      needs of individuals with Down syndrome and how
             day  is  dedicated  to raising  awareness  about  the   we,  as  future healthcare professionals, can make
             rights, inclusion, and well-being of individuals with   a difference.
             Down syndrome, while highlighting the importance
             of diversity  and  acceptance  in  every  community.   Social Inclusion:  Encouraging acceptance, respect,

             At the Faculty of Pharmacy, we believe in fostering   and  equal  opportunities  for  individuals  with
             a  culture  of  inclusivity,  compassion,  and     Down  syndrome  m  all  areas  of  life.
             understanding.  People  with  Down  syndrome       Support Systems: Highlighting the role of families,
             possess unique qualities that enrich our society, and   communities,  and  healthcare  professionals  in
             they  deserve  equal  opportunities  in  education,   providing  strong support networks for individuals
             healthcare, and beyond. As future pharmacists, it's   with Down syndrome.
             essential  to  understand  the  medical  and  social
             aspects of Down syndrome to provide better care,
             support, and guidance.

             Today, we encourage all students, faculty, and staff to reflect on how we can contribute to creating an inclusive
             environment, whether through awareness, advocacy, or simply by showing kindness and respect. Let's break
             the   barriers,   embrace     the   differences,    and   stand    together    for   inclusion.







































                                     https://www.facebook.com/share/r/TWKgZFTqQ3hudW3t/
                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I 43]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                                          A Visit to Baheya Hospital
                                                   24 April 2024






             Within the framework of enhancing the practical    The  visit  began  with  an  exploratory  tour  of the
             and  educational  interaction  of  students  of  the   various  departments  of  the  hospital,  which
             Faculty  of Pharmacy,  and under the patronage of   provided the opportunity for students to understand
             Prof.  Dr.  Cherif  Youssef  Khater- President     the health care process comprehensively,  followed
             of the University, and the leadership of Assoc. Prof.   by a tour inside the hospital and learning about the
             Dr.  Ahmed Al-Sheikh  - Director  of the  Pharm-D   drugs  used  and  the  role  of  the  pharmacist  in
             Clinical  Pharmacy  Program  at  the  Faculty  of   the health care process.
             Pharmacy,  and  the  supervision  of  Dr.  Basant
             Maher, and Dr.  Karim Saad, Dr. Ahmed Hassan.      This  visit  is  a  valuable opportunity  for  faculty's
                                                                students  to  apply  the theoretical knowledge they
             On Wednesday morning, April  24,  the  faculty  of   have  gained  in  clinical  pharmacy  to  practical
             Pharmacy  organized  a  visit  to  Baheya  Hospital,   reality, and to  enhance their  understanding  of the
             with the aim of enhancing practical understanding   vital  role  that  pharmacists  play  in  the
             of  the  healthcare  process  and  providing  field   healthcare team.
             learning opportunities, and this visit comes as part
             of  a  series  of  educational  activities  aimed  at
             deveoping  students'  skills  and  enhancing
             interaction  with  a  healthy  environment.








































                                                                        https://www.facebook.com/share/18wHR2uJ8K/
                                                                        https://www.facebook.com/share/1D3zg2bMU1/

         44  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                                In the Context of Activating Peer-to-Peer
                            Learning Initiatives: Canva Design Workshop






            As part of the ongoing efforts to foster peer-to-peer learning initiatives, the Student Wellbeing Hub organized a
            Canva Design Workshop on Friday, March 8th, at 2:00 PM. This workshop aimed to enhance students' design
            skills using  the  popular  graphic design tool,  Canva,  which  is  widely  used for  creating  digital  content,
            presentations, and social media graphics.

            The  peer-to-peer  learning  approach  allows  students  to  learn  from  each  other  in  a  collaborative
            environment, benefiting from the shared knowledge and skills of their peers. This workshop not only introduced
            the  basics  of  Canva  but  also  offered  advanced  tips  and  techniques  for  creating
            professional  designs,  helping  students  enhance  their  creativity  and  design  abilities.


            The event was opened to all students, regardless of their level of experience with design tools, and offered a great
            opportunity     to   develop    useful    skills   for    personal    and    professional    use.

                               https://www.facebook.com/share/p/pCGu3G9Xk3Kpg3Gz/?mibextid=oFDknk


                                                          - ,G�l  . IC  J.u:,,nQ; .)Lbl �

                                                       Peer to Peer


                                                       Learning



                                                        1 - How to us  Canva

                                                       2 - Ti       ching C  nv  B  sics
                   Fro1n                                3 - Junior Designer Guide
                   Student                              4 - Prep  ring a Powerpoint


                   To                                   5 - Practical L  arning
                   Student                              6 - Vid  o D  signing B  sics



                   Your First Step
                   To Become
                   a Graphic Designer                         Live
                                                              Session

                                                                 [!]








                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  45]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                Mansoura National University Faculty of Pharmacy Wins Four Out
                  of Six Awards at theMansoura University Pharmacy Conference












































             In  recogmt10n  of  the  academic  and  research  capabilities  of  Mansoura  National  University's
             students and in an effort to broaden their knowledge in the evolving field of pharmacy, and under the patronage
             of Prof.  Cherif Khater,  President  of the  University,  and  the leadership  of Assoc.  Prof. Ahmed  El-Sheikh,
             Director of the Pharm D - Clinical Pharmacy Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy, with the supervision of
             Dr. Basant Maher, PSA Coordinator and Faculty Member, students from the Faculty of Pharmacy participated
             in  the  12th  Pharmacy  Conference  held  at  Mansoura  University  from  21st  -24th  July,  2024.

             The participation aimed to expose students to the latest research and innovations in the field of phannacy, thus
             enhancing  academic  and  professional  ties.  Moreover,  these  engagements  provide  students  with  valuable
             opportunities  to  develop  their  personal  and  professional  skills  through  interaction  with  experts  and
             specialists  in  pharmacy,  and  to  gain  insight  into  the  latest  technologies  and  research  in  the  field  of
             pharmaceutical sciences.

              For more details check the followings :



                               https://www.facebook.com/100084712745066/posts/
                               pfbid02pmych7wrsuJGo1tvbDj4rJoEHELnntTk5R8KRX6rRSHfoWW9jjqAAHVF3hE7hMN4l
                               https://www.facebook.com/100084712745066/posts/
                               pfbid06YHX34kGDK2H2pRNkCjhCVz3t78zRB4VHXc5iVGu4xHLbJW7xFMwaCFtpmr9HBERl





                                                                                           Vol. 2-Issue 2   14  7]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                                             World Hemophilia Day
                                                  17th April 2024




             At the  Faculty  of Pharmacy,  Mansoura National  University,  our students  are  not only  dedicated to  their
             academic journey  but are also passionate about contributing to important health awareness  initiatives.  In a
             recent effort to raise awareness about Hemophilia, a group of students has created a powerful video to educate
             the public about this rare but seriousbleeding disorder.

             What is Hemophilia?

             Hemophilia is a genetic disorder where the blood doesn't clot properly, leading to excessive bleeding even
             from  minor  injuries.  This  condition  occurs  because  of  a  lack  of  clotting  factors  in  the  blood.
             Why Raise Awareness?

             Despite  its  importance,  hemophilia  is  still  not  widely  understood,  and  many  people,  including
             patients  and  healthcare  providers,  may  not  be  fully  aware  of  the  latest  advancements  in
             treatment.  The  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  students  have  come  together  to  create  a  video  to:

             1. Educate the Public: Increase awareness about the causes, symptoms, and treatment options for hemophilia.
             2. Promote Early Diagnosis: Encourage early detection to prevent complications from uncontrolled bleeding.
             3. Advocate  for  Better  Care:  Highlight  the  importance  of  improving  access  to  healthcare  and  treatment
             for people living with hemophilia.












                                                                         D















                                                                                https://shorturl.at/a7R8E











                                      https://youtu.be/Pk79gWh6oeA?si=SuJvU0StVKwvmCBS

                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  49]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities







              7. Improving Focus and Overcoming Procrastination: The session also delved into the science of focus and
              procrastination,  providing  strategies  to  maintain  attention  and  overcome  common  distractions
              duringstudy sessions.
























                                                                                  kU____

























                                      9 Online session
                                      @10:00pm
                    https://www.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=370729149118617&id=100085446049506&mibextid=oFDknk


             For more details check the followings :
                               https://www.facebook.com/share/p/q1JuZ9JQgQKvZUpH/?mibextid=WC7FNe
















                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  51]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                                 Activation of Eco-tourism for Students
                             Celebration of the "World Environment Day"





             In the collaboration between  community services committee and
             student  wellbeing  hub,  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  at  Mansoura
             National University organized a trip to Port Said City to visit Ashtum
             Al-Jamil nature  reserve.  Under  the  patronage  of Prof.  Dr.  Cherif
             Khater, President of the University, and the leadership of Assoc. Prof.
             Dr. Ahmed El-Sheikh, Director of the Pharm D- Clinical Pharmacy
             Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy, with the supervision of Assoc.
             Prof.  Dr.  Amal  Soliman,  Community  Services  Committee
             Coordinator,  Dr.  Heba Samir, Student Wellbeing  Hub Coordinator,
             and Dr. Ahmed Hassan, staff member.
             The trip included  varies  activity  programs  with  breathing  natural
             scenery and engaging the surrounding environment, highlighting the
             importance  of  environmental  conservation  and  increased  its
             awareness.  Students  also  participated  in  various  recreational
             activities  throughout  the  day.  The  trip  aimed  to  promotion
             eco-tourism  and  increasing  environmental  awareness  among
             the students.










































                                       https://www.facebook.com/share/p/vhx9sVQiNSYJ5pPx/


          52  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                                    Student Wellbeing Hub Ambassadors
                                    Spread Joy on World Happiness Day





              The  Student  Wellbeing  Hub  Ambassadors  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  Mansoura  National
              University, celebrated World Happiness Day with an uplifting and joyful event! On March 20th, 2024, the
             ambassadors  organized  activities  that  aimed  to  spread  positivity,  enhance  well-being,
             and encourage everyone to focus on the importance of happiness in their lives.


              World  Happiness  Day  is  an  occasion  to  remind  ourselves  of  the  significance  of  mental  and
              emotional  well-being.  The  Student  Wellbeing  Hub  played  an  essential  role  m  fostering  a
              cheerful  atmosphere,  with  activities  designed  to  bring  smiles  to  faces  and  create  an  encouraging
              environment for all students and staff.



              This  celebration  aligns  with  our  ongoing  commitment  to  promoting  mental  health  and
              happiness  as  key  components  of  a  successful  academic  and  personal  life.  The  ambassadors
             provided  various  activities  that  encouraged  students  to  take  a  moment  to  appreciate  the  little
             joys of life, fostering a supportive and positive community spirit.















































                                  https://www.facebook.com/100085446049506/videos/2081111748955969


                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  53]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Chapter 2




                                             Video Editing Session

                                   A Peer-to-peer Learning Techniques




            At Mansoura National University, the Student Wellbeing Hub is dedicated to fostering both academic growth
            and personal  development.  In line with  this mission,  we are  excited to  announce a  Video Editing Workshop
            designed to empower students with new skills and enhancetheir ability to communicate and collaborate creatively.


             The session, led by experienced students, covered the following key areas:
             I.Basic Video Editing Techniques: Leaming how to use popular editing software (e.g., Adobe Premiere, Final Cut
             Pro,  or  free  tools  like  Shotcut  and  Da Vinci  Resolve)  to  edit  videos  effectively.
            2. Storytelling Through Video:  Discovering  how to craft a  compelling  narrative,  structure yourvideo, and use
            visuals and audio to enhance storytelling.
             3.Practical  Tips  and Tricks:  Exploring  time-saving  shortcuts,  creative  editing  techniques,  and ways  to make
            your videos more professional-looking.
            4. Collaborative Project  Work: Participants  had  the  opportunity  to  work  together  on  a  shortvideo  project,
            applying what they learned in real-time.

             The  Video  Editing  Session  was  more  than  just  a  technical  workshop  - it's  a  chance  to  build
            community and develop essential skills that helped students both academically and personally. Whether you want
            to enhance your academic presentations,  create content for social  media,  or simply epress yourself creatively,
            this session was designed to support all students.
                                         https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1CT9NqvNN5/


                                  �,,

                                �        n
                                  '  0  t·  me session
                                    Video


                                                     'I
                                                   t•


                         From student to stude
                            Vot.tr first step to became a
                            video editor 9ou will learn:


                            1- Making a professional video

                            2-Effective use of filters
                           3 -Professional montage and music choice

                           4- Making cinema videos
                                    � Frida� 19 April At 9:00 P. M

                         Organized by :STUDENT WELLBEING HUB



         54  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                                       A Workshop on How to Create a
                                      Professional Account on Linkedln





             In  a  recogmt10n  to  support  the  professional  development  of  pharmacy  students  at  Mansoura
             National  University,  the  Student  Wellbeing  Hub  organized  an  exclusive  workshop  titled
             "Creating  a  Professional  Linkedln Account".  The session was aimed  at  helping  students  build  a  strong
             personal  brand  and  enhance  their  online  presence  on  Linkedln  to  better  navigate  the
             competitive job market that was introduced by Dr. Bassant Maher, staff member.


              Workshop Overview:

              The  workshop  focused  on providing  pharmacy  students  with the necessary  tools  to  develop  acompelling
              Linkedin profile. Key topics included:
              •Crafting an Effective Linkedln Profile: Students were guided on how to create a standout Linkedln profile by
             highlighting  their  skills,  educational  background,  and  accomplishments,making  them  more  visible  to
              potential employers and recruiters.
              •Networking Strategies:  The session emphasized the importance of building a strong network on  Linkedln.
              Students were introduced to strategies for connecting with professionals, faculty, and peers in the pharmacy
              and healthcare sectors.
              •Career Advancement Through Linkedln:  Participants  were shown how to use Linkedln not  only  to  find
              internships  and  research  opportunities  but  also  to  position  themselves  for  future  employment  in  the
              pharmaceutical field.

                                         https://www.facebook.com/share/p/14DyX1WzLt/








































                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  55]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                                            Student Wellbeing Hub
                                         Preparation for Eid Al-Fitr








             At  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  Mansoura  National
             University,  we  recognize that  Eid is  not just a  time for
             feasting and celebration,  but also a chance for self-care,
            wellbeing, and spiritual renewal. In the spirit of Eid, the
            Wellbeing Hub is here  to support students  in preparing
             for this important occasion in a way that promotes health,
             happiness, and balance.


             Key Areas for Eid Al-Fitr Preparation:

             Practice Mindfulness: Take moments during Eid to reflect
             on  the  blessings  in  your  life.  Practice  gratitude  and
             minfulness   to   stay   grounded   and   present.

             Social  Connection:  Eid is  about  connecting  with  family
             and friends.  Take time to nurture these relationships, and
             don't  hesitate  to  seek  support  if  you're  feeling  over­
            whelmed or isolated.





             Balance  Rest and Reflection:  Give yourself time  for  rest and  quiet moments of reflection.  W  h ether through
             prayer,  meditation,  or  quiet  contemplation,  make  time  for  activities  that  nourish  your  soul.


             Community  and  Support:  The  Wellbeing  Hub  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  is  here  to  support  students
             during this festive season. If you need any resources or guidance on maintaining your wellbeing during Eid,
             feel free to reach out. We're a community that supports each other.




             For more details check the followings :
                              https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=742666854347493&rdid=1sYidD0uaQ87kHOk



















         56  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities






                                           Solar Eclipse Awareness




















































             When the Earth, Moon, and Sun are almost in line with one another, with the Moon in the center, an eclipse
             known as a solar eclipse takes place. This occurs at the start of the lunar month, during the new moon phase.
             In this instance, the Moon throws a shadow over Earth, and if we are able to watch the eclipse, we will see the
             Moon's dark disc pass over the Sun's dazzling disk.

             At the Faculty of Pharmacy, we encourage all our students and faculty members to appreciate the science and
             beauty behind this extraordinary event. While our students are  future healthcare professionals, it's important
             to remember that our role extends beyond the human body.

             Understanding  the  natural  world  and  fostering  a  sense  of curiosity  and  wonder  about  the  umverse,
             enriches our education and shapes our scientific mindset.

             For more details check the followings :









                                        https://www.facebook.com/share/p/xn1AxnL3kei6YcXs/
                                                                                           Vol. 2-Issue 2   I  57]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Chapter 2






                                       Celebrating World Earth Day






              At  the Faculty  of Pharmacy, Mansoura National �-�



              University, we are committed to not only promoting   �
              health and wellbeing but also taking steps to care   �JlnJI
              for our planet. On April 22nd, we join the global   ••
              community in celebrating World Earth Day, a day                    April 22, 2024
              dedicated  to  environmental  protection,  raising
              awareness about climate change,  and  encouraging                   :  J  lD.w t::.
              sustainable  practices  fora  healthier  Earth.                 .cl,µ'4JI J!liio c.,JgSJI
                                                                     o=lg 6 JO p� c..$::ill c..!14)1 cf:lg.il � ,lzn.ill og.c.::i
             This year, the celebration is held under the slogan     ,6.l. uugl.o Jb::l l}D ail up o.io ._p.I l}D (JSo t.=,
                             W
             Planet vs. Plastic.  h ere plastic is one of the most
             dangerous  pollutants  because  it  contains  harmful
             substances,  the  most  important  of which is  the
             chemical  dioxin  that  causes  cancer.  Therefore,
              please  follow  the  following  tips  to  avoid
             the dangers of plastic:


              1-Do  not  put  plastic  utensils  in  the  microwave
             2-Do  not  put  plastic  bottles  in  the  freezer
              3-Do  not  wrap  any  hot  food  in  plastic


             For more details check the followings :






















                                           https://www.facebook.com/share/p/18wqYcEw4r/








         58  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                      Mother's Day Celebration at the Faculty of Pharmacy,
                                       Mansoura National University






             Mother's  Day,  celebrated  annually  on  March  21st,  is  a  special  occasion  dedicated  to  honoring  and
             appreciating the immense role that mothers play  in the lives of their children and in society.  It is a day to
             express  gratitude  and  admiration  for  the  love,  sacrifice,  and  care  mothers  provide,  shaping
             the future of generations.

             At the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  Mansoura  National  University,  we acknowledge  the  invaluable  contributions
             of mothers to education and family life. This day serves as a reminder for everyone to appreciate the support
             and love given by mothers, not juston Mother's Day but every day.
             On  this  day,  students,  faculty,  and  staff  come  together  to  celebrate  mothers  with  thoughtful
             gestures, words  of appreciation,  and recognition  of their hard work.  Whether through gifts,  kind words, or
             spending  quality  time,  Mother's  Day  allows  us  to  show  our  love  and  respect  for  the  women
             who nurture and guide us.
             Mother's  Day  is  not  just  a  celebration,  but  a  reminder  of  the  continuous  support  that  mothers
             provide in every aspect of our lives. Let us all take this opportunity to honor the mothers who are at the heart of
             our community and families.









                                                    llappg






                             /IIIOTIIE                               'SOAY!




















                                     )

                             https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=375077412017124&set=a.163093663215501




                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  59]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Chapter 2





                               Training Program for Pharmacy Students
                         at Mansoura National University at Bahia Hospital






           In a  continuous  effort  to  enhance  the  practical  and   The  training  program  covered  a  range  of  topics and
           clinical  skills  of  pharmacy  students,  the  Faculty  of   hands-on  activities  related  to  clinical  pharmacy,
           Pharmacy at Mansoura National University organized a   including:
          specialized training program for its students at Baheya
           Hospital.  This  program,  held  under  the  guidance and   I .Pharmaceutical  Care  in  Oncology:  Students
          supervision of esteemed faculty members with Baheya's   learned  about  t h e  role  of  pharmacists  in  the
           clinical  pharmacists,  aims  to  provide  students  with   treatment  of  b r east  cancer  patients,  including
           first  hand  experience  in  a  clinical  environment,   medication management and the provision of advice on
          improving their understanding of real-world  pharmacy   drug   interactions   and     side    effects.
           practices.
                                                                2.Patient  Counseling:  Emphasis  was  placed  on
                                                               effective  communication  with  patients,  guiding  them
                                                                t h rough   their   medication   regimens,   and
                                                               ensuring    p r oper   usage   of   prescriptions.
              BAHEYA SUMMER TRAINING

              Bahya  Foundation  for  Early  Detection  &  Treatment  of   3.Hands-on  Practice  in  Clinical  Pharmacy,
              Breast Cancer Introduces:
                                                               Surgical  Pathology,  and  Infection  Control
               A clinical pharmacy training program for Faculty of Pharmacy Mansoura
                      National University students. accredited by
                the American Association of Continuing Medical Education {AACME).
                                                               4.Interdisciplinary      Collaboration:      The
               OBTAINED KNOWLEDGE
              @ Breast cancer awareness & management plan (surgery.   program  highlighted  the  importance  of  teamwork
                medlcal oncology, radiotherapy, radio diagnosis &
                physiotherapy departments) added to  research and   between  healthcare  professionals  in  delivering
                biostatistics principles through online sessions.
              @ Hands-on training In clinical pharmacy. surgical   optimal patient care.
                pathology lab., and infection conuol.
              DURATION OF THE COURSE
              @ 7 Work;ng D  ys (40 hr  .)                     Through this initiative, the Faculty of Pharmacy at MNU
                                                               aims  to  produce  well-rounded  pharmacists  equipped
                PROGRAM DETAILS
                                                               with  the  necessary  skills  to  excel  in  their  careers.



           For more details check the followings :















                                   https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?
                                   story_fbid=pfbid02dXQMVRoJ573KM8iVnhgJR2iwNUZ4Axp1SDxrt
                                   BJ84AXhWCqfDkTNVQcj8Afby1bXl&id=100085446049506


         60  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[Extra-curricular Student Activities





                                   Opening of Applications for Summer
                              Term Courses and Workshops "July 2024"







             The  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  at  Mansoura  National  University  was  pleased  to  announce  the
             opening  of  applications  for  its  Summer  Term  courses  and  workshops.  These  programs  were
             designed to provide pharmacy students with valuable opportunities to enhance their academic and practical
             skills.  The  courses  and  workshops  covered  various  topics  related  to  pharmacy
             education  and  practice,  aiming  to  equip  students  with  the  knowledge  needed  for  their
             professional  development.  Interested  students  were  invited  to  apply  and  benefit  from  these
             enriching learning experiences.











                 .. ..       II  II   I •r  '  I IJ)   . ·-·  . .
                                                     . .
                                                    . .
                              P  OGRAM
                                                                                        Comprehensive
                                                                                       Entrepreneurship
                                                                                             Course













             For more details check the followings :


                           https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=446437491547782&set=pcb.446438021547729




















                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  61]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Chapter 3
          I                      Commencement of the First Workshop for                                        I





                                 Reviewing the University's Strategic Plan




          In an effort to  enhance the quality of education and  Assoc. Prof. Dr. Ahmed El-Sheikh began the session by
          promote  academic  excellence,  and  under  the       presenting  the  key  components  of  the  university's
          patronage  of Prof. Dr. Cherif  Khater,  the University   strategic  plan,  followed  by  a  discussion  of  the
          President, and the leadership of Assoc. Prof. Dr. Ahmed   university's human and material resources, as well as its
          El-Sheikh,  Director  Pharm  D-Clinical  Pharmacy     organizational structure. He also outlined the phases of
          Program at the Faculty of Pharmacy and Coordinator of   the  plan's  development,  explaining  its  foundational
          Quality, Accreditation, and Social Responsibilty at the   references, standard measurements, and data collection
          University,  with the presence of Prof.  Raeefa Allam,   tools. During his speech, he emphasized the importance
          Dean of the Faculty of Nursing, and the kind hosting of   of studying  the university's  distinctive features while
          Prof.  Noha  El-Waseefi,  Director  of  the  Dentistry   formulating the strategic plan's elements, naming core
          Program at  the  Faculty  of  Dentistry,  the  University   values,  and  adopting  governing  policies.  He  then
          began its first workshop for reviewing the 2024-2029   presented the  results  of the  environmental analysis,
          strategic plan.                                       which included internal and external analyses, defining
                                                                strategic  goals,  and  identifying the  gap  between  the
          The  workshop,  held  on  Wednesday,  February  14th,   c u rrent   state   and   future   aspirations.
           involved  the  participation  of  the  strategic  planning
          team, along with representatives from the faculties. It   Prof. Dr.  Raeefa Allam highlighted the importance of
          was attended by faculty members, assistant staff, and   the strategic plan as a vital foundation for achieving the
          several administrative team members from across the   university's goals and mission, setting future directions,
          university  to analyze  data  and  set  strategic  goalsfor   priorities,  improving education and scientific research
          the future.                                           quality,  and  meeting  the  needs  and  aspirations
                                                                of students.

                                                                Following the presentations, the strategic planning team
                                                                members  were  divided  into  smaller  work  groups  to
                                                                begin brainstorming sessions and discussions to review
                                                                the formulation of  objectives,  performance standards,
                                                                and the  goals  of  the proposed strategic  plan  for  the
                                                                university.


                                                                It  is  worth  mentioning  that  workshops  continued
                                                                periodically  until the strategic plan was finalized and
                                                                approved.

                                                                 https://www.facebook.com/share/p/xs6SKRnCsGcCEnJM/?
                                                                 mibextid=WC7FNe


          For more details check the followings :












         64  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Campus News: Updates and Faculty Insights

         I                    Awareness at Mansoura National University                                       I



                              Promoting Occupational Safety and Health






           To enhance awareness of the  importance  of occupational  safety  and  health  in the  workplace,  and  to  equip
           university  members  with  knowledge  of  safe  practices,  Mansoura  National  University  organized  its  first
          Occupational Safety  and  Health Initiative  on  Wednesday,  February  14th,  2024,  under  the  title  "Your  Safety
          Matters."  This  event aimed  to  create  a  safer  and  healthier  campus environment  for  all  students  and  staff.

          The event was held under the patronage of Prof. Dr. Cherif Khater, President of the University, and organized by
          Assoc.  Prof.  Dr. Ahmed  El-Sheikh  Director  of  the  Pharma  D-Clinical  Pharmacy  Program  at  the  Faculty  of
           Pharmacy,  the  Coordinator  for  Quality,  Accreditation,  and  Social  Responsibilty.  It  was  conducted  in
          collaboration with the  Directorate of Labor in  Dakahlia,  in  coordination with the  Ministry  of Labor's General
          Department  for  Workplace  Safety.  The  initiative  was  attended  by  a  wide  range  of  university  members,
          including both students and staff.


          The  session  began  with  Assoc.  Prof.  Dr.  Ahmed  El-Sheikh,  who  delivered  a  speech  on  the  significance  of
          occupational safety and health and its role in protecting facilities and the workforce. Prof. Dr. Raeefa Allam, Dean
          of  the  Faculty  of Nursing,  highlighted  the  importance  of  spreading  safety  and  health  awareness  within
          educational institutions.

















































                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  65]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Chapter 3






           Dr. Abdelghani Weza spoke about the "Your Safety Matters" initiative and its role in raising awareness across various
           institutions and activities within the governorate. Additionally, Mrs. Mona El Hadidi, the Occupational Safety and
           Health  Officer  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  emphasized  the  critical  role  of  these  initiatives  in
           promoting safety in organizations.



           The  initiative  included  several  key  lectures.  The  first  lecture  was  presented  by  Eng.  Islam  Hamdy  from  the
           Central Administration for Occupational Safety and Workplace Environment Security at the Ministry of Labor, where
           he discussed emergency and evacuation plans, their purpose, and requirements. The second lecture, by Eng. Asmaa
           Adel, Director of the Mit Ghamr office, focused on how to form safety and health committees within organizations
           and the role of each member in protecting workers and facilities. Dr. Ayman Abdelhamid, a consultant in occupational
           safety and health, concluded the session with a lecture on risk management and analysis, emphasizing its importance
           in reducing injuries and losses.


           It is worth noting that the Ministry of  Labor launched the "Your Safety Matters" initiative in October under the
           leadership of Minister Hassan Shihata, aimed at spreading a culture of occupational safety and health among workers
           to  protect  them  from  workplace  hazards  and  provide  a  safe  working  environment.  The  event  was
           organized by Mrs. Mona El Hadi, the Occupational Safety and Health Officer at the Faculty of Pharmacy, along with
           Mr.  Amir  Philip,  the  administrative  officer  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  and  Mrs.  Dina  Emad,
           the Community Engagement Officer at the university.



           This  initiative  reflects  the  university's  ongoing  commitment  to  creating  a  safe  and  supportive  environment
           for  its  community,  reinforcing  the  importance  of  safety  in  both  academic  and  work-related  settings.






           For more details check the followings :


                                 https://www.facebook.com/share/dBAqaJhQyX5tpWsf/?mibextid=WC7FNe






























         66  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Campus News: Updates and Faculty Insights

         I      Course in Collaboration with the German Academic Exchange Service                             I



                                                                              T
                  Problem-Solving and Teamwork Enhancement:  h e First Training






            As part of the university's ongoing efforts to train its staff, Mansoura National University  organized a training
            session  on  "Problem-Solving  and  Teamwork  Enhancement"  on  Saturday,  March  9th.  The  event  was  held  in
            collaboration  with  the  German  Academic  Exchange  Service  (DAAD)  in  Cairo,  under  the  patronage  of Prof.
            Cherif Khater,  University President, and the leadership of Assoc. Prof. Ahmed El-Sheikh, Director of the Pharm
            D  - Clinical  Pharmacy  Program  and  Coordinator  of Quality,  Accreditation,  and  Community  Engagement  at
            the university.

            The training aimed to enhance problem-solving skills and promote teamwork among university staff.  It included
            an  introduction  to  problem  identification  and  provided  practical  methods  and  tools  for  creative  thinking  and
            effective collaboration. The course also covered team formation,  how to select a team leader, and the essential
            qualities  a  leader  should  possess,  in  addition  to  group  discussions  for  idea  exchange  among  participants.

            This  training  session  is  part  of  the  university's  continuous  efforts  to  improve  the  quality  of
            education,  enhance  the  work  environment,  and  develop  the  skills  and  capabilities  of  its  workforce.

                                https://www.facebook.com/share/p/873bpMfRt4WDPqpg/?mibextid=oFDknk
































            For more details check the followings :














                                                                                           Vol. 2-Issue 2   I  67]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[Campus News: Updates and Faculty Insights








          The  session  featured  esteemed  experts  in  the   The  convening  of  this  roundtable  came  within  the
           pharmaceutical  field,  including  Dr.  Mohamed     framework  of  activating  the  role  of  the  external
          EI-Naggar,  senior  first-line  business  manager,  Dr.   community and the job market in identifying the needs
          Mhamed  Wanas,  Line  Manager  of  the  Consumer     of graduates  and  ensuring their  qualification  with  the
           Health  Team  at  Epico,  Dr.  Ahmed  Kotb,  Sandoz   latest  necessary  skills  for  success  in the  job  market.
          District  Manager,  Dr.  Khaled Kheer, First-Line  Sales   The  university  embraces  these  initiatives  as  an
           Manager-Jamjoom  Pharma  Egypt,  Dr.  Mahmoud       essential part of its vision for developing education and
          Albittar,  Executive  Trainer- Nerhadou,  Dr.  Khaled   improving  the  educational  services  provided  to  its
           Shaher,  General Coordinator-ED  Pharma,  Dr.  Ahmed   students.
          Mokhtar,  Business  Consultant- Dmass  &  Somy,
           Dr.  Mohamed  EI-Farahaty,  Area  Supervisor-Eva
          Pharma,     Dr,   Mohamed      Tarek,   District
           Manager-Pharma  Right,  Dr.  Abdalla Al-Iraqi,  District
          Manager- Bluebell,  Dr.  Mohamed  Salah,  District
           Manager- Majestic Biopharma.


                      https://www.facebook.com/story.php?
                      story_fbid=368047372720128&id=100085446049506&mibextid=oFDknk&rdid=6TzR2am4SPvQR9og


















































                                                                                           Vol. 2-Issue 2   I  69]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Chapter 3
          I                                Awareness Campaign on                                               I





                                             World Innovation Day










           On the occasion of the World Innovation Day,  the
           students  of  the  Faculty     of  Pharmacy,
           Mansoura  National  University,  conducted  an
           awareness campaign on the  World Innovation  Day
           and  made  posters  on  important  topics  such  as
           entrepreneurship  and  the  qualities  of a  successful
           entrepreneur  such  as  creativity,  innovation,
           risk  tolerance,  effective  leadership  and  other
           qualities.  Students  hung  these  posters  in
           different places in the college.


           For more details check the followings :

                https://www.facebook.com/share/v/1CR37sxzcg/















































         70  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[https://www.facebook.com/share/p/19KKsNQAYP/]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Campus News: Updates and Faculty Insights

         I    Mentors Company to Promote Entrepreneurship in the Pharmaceutical Sector                        I



                  Signing A Cooperation Protocol Between the Faculty of Pharmacy and







           In a step that reflects the aspiration of Faculty of Pharmacy  towards achieving excellence and innovation in the
          field of pharmaceutical sciences,  and within the framework of Mansura National University's efforts to achieve
           academic excellence by providing a supportive environment for entrepreneurship and innovation,  and under the
           patronage  of  Prof.  Cherif  Khater  - President  of  the  University,  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  signed  a
          cooperation protocol with Mentors on Monday, April 29, where the protocol was signed by Assoc. Prof. Dr. Ahmed
          El-Sheikh  - Director  Pharm  D  Clinical  Pharmacy  Program  at  the  Faculty  of  Pharmacy,
           Coordinator of Quality, Accreditation and Social Responsibility representing the University, Dr. Mohamed Serry -
          Director  of  Mentors  Company  representing  the  company,  and  coordination  of  Dr.  Randa  Hani  -
           Protocol Coordinator.


           The  protocol  aims  to  expand  the  horizons  of  entrepreneurship  in  the  field  of  pharmacy  by
          exploiting the services  and resources  available  to  the  company  and the  protocol  also  includes  the  benefit  of
           faculty's  students  from the  business  support  services  provided  by  the  company,  such  as providing  strategic
          consultations,  and  directing  students  in  Faculty  of  Pharmacy  towards  new  opportunities  for  innovation
           and development in the pharmaceutical field.

           The  signing  of  the  protocol  stems  from  the  belief  of  both  the  University  administration  and
          Faculty of Pharmacy in serving the surrounding community, as the cooperation includes a unique experience to
          establish a special system for pharmacists and entrepreneurs.




























           For more details check the followings :










                                        https://www.facebook.com/share/p/1ASS5ERnDY/
                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  73]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[Chapter 3
          I    "The Effective Role of thePharmacist in Hypertension Cases Blood Pressure"                      I



                    Faculty of Pharmacy Participates in World Hypertension Day Event








           Under  the patronage of Prof.  Dr.  Cherif Youssef
           Khater,  President  of  the  University  and  the
           supervision  of Assoc.  Prof.  Dr. Ahmed  El-Sheikh,
           Director  of the  Faculty  of Pharmacy  Program  and
           within  the  framework  of  community  participation;
           Dr.  Randa  Haney,  Community  Engagement
           Coordinator at the Faculty of Pharmacy, participated
           in  the  activities  of  the  World  Hypertension  Day
           entitled  'The  effective  role  of the  pharmacist  with
           blood pressure cases', organized by the Pharmacists
           Syndicate  in  Damietta  in  cooperation  with  the
           Egyptian Society  for Hypertension, in the presence
           of Prof. Dr. Soliman Gharib, Professor of Cardiology
           at  the  Faculty  of  Medicine,  and  Prof.  Dr.
           Mohamed Mohsen, Professor of Cardiology, Faculty
           of  Medicine,  Cairo  University,  and  Dr.  Khaled
           El-Nagdy, Damietta Pharmacists Syndicate, and Dr.
           Abdel  Gawad,  Undersecretary  of the  Ministry  of
           Health,  and  Dr.  Assem  El  Akabawy,  Head  of
           Commercial Sector at EPICO.


           For  his  part,  Dr.  Wafaa  Al-Aroussi,  Dr.  Heba
           Al-Deeb, and Dr. Ghada Sayed praised the role of the                           .u1���
           society  to  raise awareness of the dangers of blood                                       "'4  �  I
           pressure  and  activate  initiatives  to  educate                             ..:. ... ,,...iu   _;:�· ,_   , ....... ;;:;:::
                                                                                             '.;.._,, ....  · ........... ....
           phannacists about proper measurement methods, and
           Dr. Assem Al-Aqbawi stressed the social role of the
           company  and  its  interest  in  the  initiatives
           implemented by the society.




           For more details check the followings :




                                                                     https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid













         7  4  I   Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Campus News: Updates and Faculty Insights

         I  Entrepreneurialism" Award In the Times Higher Education Arab World Awards 2024                    I



              Mansoura National University Is Nominated for The "Outstanding Contribution to









           Mansoura  National  University  is  pleased  to
          announce  that  it  has  been  nominated  for  the
           "Outstanding  Contribution  to  Entrepreneurialism"
          award in the Times Higher Education A w ards for the
          Arab World for 2024. This award comes to honor
          academic  institutions  that  have  made  outstanding
           contributions  in  the  field  of entrepreneurship  and
          innovation,  and  to  honor  the  continuous  efforts
          exerted  by  the  university  under  the  patronage  of
          Prof. Dr. Cherif Khater, President of the University,
          and  the  leadership  of Assoc.  Prof.  Dr.  Ahmed
          El-Sheikh,  Responsible  for  Quality, Accreditation,
          and Social Responsibility at the university, and Dr.
          Randa Hani, Community Participation Officer at the
          Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  in  promoting  the
          entrepreneurial environment and providing optimal
          opportunities  to  develop  entrepreneurial  skills.

          This  nomination  is  an  important  step  towards
          realizing the university's vision to be a leader in the
          field  of  higher  education  and  innovation










           For more details check the followings :

                           https://www.facebook.com/photo?fbid=457296453770776&set=pcb.457049457128809





















                                                                                           Vol. 2 - Issue 2   I  7  5]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[Chapter 3
          I                       Small Business Management Workshop                                           I



                                     Essentials of Entrepreneurship and








          Faculty  of  Pharmacy,  Mansoura  National  University  participated  in  workshop  organized  by  the  German
          Academic  Exchange  Service  (DAAD)  titled  "Essentials  of  Entrepreneurship  and  Small  Business
          Management".  In  the  framework  of  the  DKA  a  two-day  workshop  was  conducted  by  Ms.  Amany
           Ramadan  on  the  premises  of  the  DAAD  Regional  Office  Cairo  in  Zamalek  on  7th  and  8th  July,  2024.

          The  following  aspects,  among  others,  have  been  intensively  covered  and  discussed:

                                          e
           -Foundation       and      entr p r eneurship
           -Designing  a  competitive  business  model
          -Types  of  entrepreneurs  and  entrepreneurships
           -Social  entrepreneurs  and  social  entrepreneurship
           -Business prototyping
           -Building   a   powerful    marketing    plan
           -Crafting   a    winning     b u siness   p l an

           The workshop was attended by 22 participants and included many group activities in which the participants have
           practiced  models  of business  plans  and  initiatives  and  got  feedback  from  both  trainer  and  other  participants.

                                  https://www.facebook.com/share/p/141Janq7Hh/?mibextid=WC7FNe












































         76  I    Faculty of Pharmacy Newsletter]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[Campus News: Updates and Faculty Insights
         I    "Excellence in Education, Innovation in Care."                                                  I











































                                                                          •












































                                                                                           Vol. 2 -Issue 2   I  77]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[https://www.facebook.com/share/1JPtLAfbHW/]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>